# **YASH** ANAND

## Software Engineer

A passion for web applications, programming languages, and computer systems, with a track record of delivering high-quality solutions for both enterprise and product-based startups. Master's from a top CS school, with experience that spans researching WebAssembly, as well as designing and implementing kernels and optimizing compilers.

#### **HONORS** -

Director's Scholarship Carnegie Mellon Univ. (2022)

**Special Recognition Award** Shell (2022)

**VP CIO Award** Shell (2021)

**Service Recognition Award** Shell (2021)

#### **EDUCATION** -

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

**Master of Software Engineering** Carnegie Mellon University, School of CS CGPA: 3.9/4 • Pittsburgh, PA, U.S.A

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology Vellore Institute of Technology CGPA: 8.5/10 • Vellore, India

Coursework (CMU)

Operating System Design and Implementation, Compiler Design, Software Architecture, Web Applications, Advanced Formal Methods, Intro to Computer Systems

Experience (CMU)

Teaching Assistant for Web Applications Teaching Assistant for Software Architecture

#### EXPERIENCE -

Jul 2019 - Jul 2022

#### **Software Engineer** Shell

Bangalore, India (On-site)

Sep 2018 - Jul 2019

# **Lead Software Developer**

Vellore, India (Part-time, Hybrid)

Feb 2017 - Feb 2019

#### **Software Development Intern AppSecure**

Vellore, India (Part-time, Remote)

- Optimized load time of orq-wide skills and resource management applications by 70%.
- Pioneered a CI/CD initiative for the platform, and implemented mission-critical software for managing projects, resources, and security incidents across the organization.
- Winner of org-wide VP CIO Award in May 2021, and Service Recognition Awards.
- Solely developed the desktop user interface for a wearable gesture controller called Kai.
- Lead software team for a product that raised over \$100k via crowdfunding on Indiegogo.
- While simultaneously pursuing an undergraduate degree, built the entire web eco-system including UI component libraries, product website, auth intermediary, and many more.
- Single-handedly developed and designed multiple security-based SaaS apps during the start-up's foundational years while simultaneously pursuing an undergraduate degree.
- Pivotal work that contributed to start-up's listing in Forbes 30 under 30 Asia in 2017.
- Built a web app (rakshak.io) that was acclaimed at the RISE Conference in 2018.

#### **PROJECTS**

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

# Pebbles Kernel & Hypervisor C, x86 Assembly

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

## **WASM Dynamic Analysis** WebAssembly, Rust, Virgil

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

#### C Compiler

OCaml, x86, WebAssembly

Carnegie Mellon • 2023

#### Dynamic Memory Allocator C, Linux

Carnegie Mellon • 2022

#### Chesster

JavaScript, Python, Django

- Implemented a Unix-like kernel for x86 with a robust user thread library, loader, drivers, with preemptive multitasking, multi-threading, demand paging, Copy-on-Write, etc.
- Type 1 hypervisor capable of running quest kernels, with support for virtual consoles.
- Developed dynamic analysis and instrumentation tools for a WebAssembly engine.
- Submitted a paper to ASPLOS titled "Flexible Non-intrusive Dynamic Instrumentation for WebAssembly" evaluating several well-known techniques against our novel design.
- Designed and constructed a memory-safe optimizing compiler for a subset of the C language achieving runtime performance on par with the industry-standard GCC (-01).
- Features included strings, function pointers, arrays, structs, and a WebAssembly target.
- Implemented a high-performance dynamic memory allocator surpassing the efficiency of C's standard malloc package for a diverse set of program traces.
- Achieved rank 1 performance & utilization in 15213 summer '23 class of 150 students.
- Built a fully-functional online chess multiplayer game that featured in-game spectators, live chat, and a global live feed of top-spectated games.
- Uses vanilla JavaScript and WebSockets for all it's complex asynchronous interactions.

Tools/Technologies Top Skills Languages Web Applications Kernel Programming C C++ JavaScript x86 Assembly Vim React Virtualization Compiler Design WebAssembly Angular **OCaml** Python Diango